A Guide to the paper of Harold J. Morowitz, 1927 -
George Mason University Libraries
- Morowitz Collection
  - Protons [folder 1 of 2] [Mitchell's Bio] 10/1947 - 1977, folder 4 (Box box 14)
    22 publications by Peter Mitchell:"Oxidation and Photosynthetic Phosphorylation: Vectorial Chemiosmotic Process, 1977; "Vectorial Chemistry and the Molecular Mechanics of Chemiosmotic Coupling: Power Transmition by Proticity, 1976; "A Chemiosmotic Molecular Mechanism for Proton-Transporting Adenosine Triphosphatases", 7/1974; "The Mechanism for Proton Translocation in Reversible Proton-Translocation Adenosine Triphosphatases", 1974; "Proton-Translocation Pyrophosphatase of Rhodospirillum Rumbrum", 6/1972; "Chemiosmotic Coupling in Energy Transduction: A Logical Development of Biochemical Knowledge", 1972; Membranes of Cells and Organelles: Morphology, transport and Metabolism", 1970; Chemiosmotic Coupling and Energy Transduction", 1968; "Bromthymol Blue as a pH Indicator in Microndrial Suspensions", 1968; "Proton-Translocation Phosphorylation in mitochondria, chloroplasts and bacteria: natural fuel cells and solor cells[sic]", 9-10/1967; "Proton Current Flow in Mitochondrial Systems", 6/24/67; "Intramitrachondrial pH: a Statistical Question of Hydrogen Ion Concentration in a Small Element of Space-time", 4/22/67; "Chemiosmotic Hypothesis of Oxidative Phosphorylation", 1/14/67; "Molecule Group and Electron Translocation Through Natural Membranes", 1963; "Group-Translocation: A Consequence of Enzyme-Catalysed Group-transfer", 8/9/58; "Transport of Phosphate Across the Surface of Micrococcus pyrogenes: Nature of the Cell Inorganic Phosphate", 10/1953; " Enzyme Catalysis and Group Translocation", 2/24/58; "The Origin of Life and the Formation and Organising Functions of Natural Membranes", 1957; "Transport of Phosphate across the Omsmotic Barrier of Micrococcus pyrogenes: Specificity and Kinetics", 1954; "The Glycerophospho-protein Complex of Envelope Micrococcus pyrogenes Paths of Phosphate Transfer in Micrococcus pyrogenes: Phosphate Turnover in Nucleic Acids and other Factions", 10/1953; "Assimilation of Amino-acids by Bacteria", 10/1947; "Occurrence of a Phosphoric Ester in Certain Bacteria: Its Relation to Gram Staining and Penicillin Sensitivity, 8/5/50.
  - Protons [2 of 2] 1976 - 1980, folder 5 (Box box 14)
    Published articles by Peter Mitchell: "The Culture of Imagination", 1980; "Protonmotive Cytochrome System of Mitcohondria", 5/31/80; "David Keilin's Respiratory Chain Concept and its Chemiosmotic Consequences", 1979; "Epilogue From Energetic Abstraction to Biochemical mechanism", 1977; Possible Molecular Mechanisms of the Protonmotive Function of Cytochrome Systems
  - Tardigrades 1/1964 - 1967, folder 1 (Box box 15)
  - Introduction Biology Course - Advanced, folder 2 (Box box 15)
    notes for an unpublished book
  - Scientific Correspondence: S.L. Slater, Universiteit Van Amsterdam 2/4/77, folder 2 (Box box 14)
  - Scientific Correspondence: R.N. Robertson 6/23/76, folder 4 (Box box 15)
  - Scientific Correspondence: Andres, Cornell University 5/26/??, folder 5 (Box box 15)
  - Scientific Correspondence: Efraim Racker, Albert Einstein Professor of Biology, Cornell Univ. 6/29/76, folder 6 (Box box 15)
  - Scientific Correspondence: Dr. Peter Mitchell 6/4/76, folder 7 (Box box 15)
  - Epitomology 11/25/78 - 3/23/79, folder 8 (Box box 15)
  - Misc Correspondence 8/26/60 - 12/8/70, folder 9 (Box box 15)
  - Teilhard 5/1/90 - 2/28/94, folder 10 (Box box 15)
    Teilhard de Chardin
  - South Pacific 2/1/74 - 2/28/76, folder 11 (Box box 15)
  - Whale Census 2/1/96 - 1/6/83, folder 12 (Box box 15)
    hump back whales in Hawian waters
  - Margulis 9/1/9411/15/95, folder 13 (Box box 15)
  - E.C. Pollard Lecture 1/24/72 - 6/14/84, folder 14 (Box box 15)
  - Letter: Lars Onsager 9/27/76, folder 15 (Box box 15)
  - Simplistic Roots of Complexity, folder 16 (Box box 15)
    unpublished essay
  - Complexity 2 10/30/91 - 12/17/96, folder 17 (Box box 15)
  - [paper on cloning and bioethics], folder 18 (Box box 15)
    hand written draft
  - [book review on No Time to Be Brief}, folder 19 (Box box 15)
  - [On the Origin and Fine Tuning of Metabolism], folder 20 (Box box 15)
  - Kinetic Treatment of the Steady State Analysis of Evolution 1965, folder 21 (Box box 15)
    unpublished paper